He always takes one
The Collector is a horror, thriller film directed by Marcus Dunstan.
Desperate to repay his debt to his ex-wife, an ex-con plots a heist at his new employer's country home, unaware
that a second criminal has also targeted the property, and rigged it with a series of deadly traps.
Arkin, played by Josh Stewart.
The Collector, played by Juan Fernández.
Michael Chase, played by Michael Reilly Burke.
Jill Chase, played by Madeline Zima.
Victoria Chase, played by Andrea Roth.
Hannah Chase, played by Karley Scott Collins.
The Collector is a 2009 American horror film written by Patrick
Melton and Marcus Dunstan, and directed by Dunstan.
It stars Josh Stewart, alongside Michael Reilly Burke, Andrea Roth, Juan
Fernandez, Karley Scott Collins, Madeline Zima, and Robert Wisdom.
The film follows handyman Arkin O'Brien (Stewart) who, in order to pay a debt, decides to rob a house, only to find
out somebody with far more sinister intentions has already broken in and rigged it with multiple traps.
The original script, titled The Midnight Man, was at one point shopped as a spin-off prequel
to the Saw franchise, as an origin story for the villain John Kramer / Jigsaw.
The producers opposed the idea and dismissed it, but the strength of the script led to
writers Marcus Dunstan and Patrick Melton writing multiple Saw films.
The Collector was released on July 31, 2009, by Freestyle Releasing.
It received generally negative reviews from critics and
grossed $10.2 million against a $3 million budget.
A sequel, The Collection, was released theatrically on November 30, 2012.
The film explores themes of fight, burglar, psychopath, home, gore.
The tone is dark and intense.